export const questionBankData = [
  {
    id: 1,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q1]",
    question: `The Central Government may, if satisfied that it is necessary that a Patent should be acquired from the Patentee for a public purpose within the provision of Patent Act, then a notification is published in:`,
    correctAnswer: "c",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: `All leading newspapers`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: ` All leading newspapers and Journals`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: `Official Gazette`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: `All of the above`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q2]",
    question: ` Choose the correct option from the following:
    Every application for a Patent shall be published under section 11A of the Act except in cases where the application-`,
    correctAnswer: "d",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: ` In which secrecy direction is imposed under section 35 of the Act`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `Has been abandoned under sub-section (1) of section 9 of the Act`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: `Has been withdrawn three months prior to the period specified under sub section (1) of section 11 A of the Act`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: `All of above`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q3]",
    question: ` In case of request for permission of making Patent application outside India as per section 39 of the Act the
    time frame to dispose such request by Controller is:`,
    correctAnswer: "c",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: `Within 30 days from the request`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `Within 6 months from the request`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: `Within 21 days from the request`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: `None of the above`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q4]",
    question: ` A Patent awarded by the Patent Office of India is valid in:`,
    correctAnswer: "c",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: `All ASEAN countries territories`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `All countries that adhere to TRIPS`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: `Indian territory`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: `All of the above`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q5]",
    question: `One PCT application with US priority is filed on 19.09.2009 and for filing National phase application in India the applicant needs to file within:`,
    correctAnswer: "a",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: `19.04.2012`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `19.09.2014`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: `19.09.2013`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: ` 19.04.2013`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q6]",
    question: ` A Patent applicant may file a Patent infringement suit within the provision of the Act only after:`,
    correctAnswer: "b",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: `Publication of the Patent application`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `Grant of the Patent application`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: `Priority date of the Patent application`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: `Date of filing of Complete Specification`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q7]",
    question: `As per The Patent Act, 1970 the first compulsory licence granted in India to:`,
    correctAnswer: "a",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: `Natco Pharma on 9th March, 2012`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `Cipla on 9th March, 2009`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: `Glenmark on 27th January, 2009`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: `None of the above`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q8]",
    question: `Method of committing theft is not Patentable in accordance to one of the Sections of the Patent Act, 1970.
    Find out the relevant section from the following:`,
    correctAnswer: "b",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: ` Section 3(c) of the Act`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `Section 3(b) of the Act`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: `Section 3(a) of the Act`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: `Section 3(d) of the Act`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q9]",
    question: `As per the Patent Act, the term of a Patent of addition filed on 13.04.2012 (granted on 15.01.2015) with re-
    gard to Complete Specification of an ordinary Patent application filed on 15.07.2008 (granted on 17.09.2011) is
    up to [considering that neither one is revoked prior to term of validity]`,
    correctAnswer: "b",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: ` 13.04.2032`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `15.07.2028`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: ` 17.09.2031`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: `15.01.2035`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q10]",
    question: `An appeal shall not lie to the Appellate Board as per the Patent Act for the following option:`,
    correctAnswer: "b",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: ` Refusal decision of a Patent application under section 15 of the Act`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `An application is deemed to be abandoned under section 21 of the Act`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: `Decision of Controller with regard to compulsory licence under section 84 of the Act.`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: `The decision related to post grant opposition under section 25(4) of the Act`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q11]",
    question: `The period for which an application for Patent shall not ordinarily be open to public in Patent Office Journal
    from the date of filing or date of priority of the application, whichever is earlier as per the provision of the Act
    (Assume that there is no request for early publication)`,
    correctAnswer: "a",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: `18 months`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `12 months`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: `6 months`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: `8 months`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q12]",
    question: ` An Indian applicant has filed an ordinary Patent application before Patent Office by filing Provisional Spec-
    ification on 12.05.2011 (assuming no postdating of application). Find out the correct option from the following:`,
    correctAnswer: "b",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: `The applicant filed the Complete Specification on 12.8.2012 after filing Form 4 on 11.05.2012 for three months
        extension`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `The applicant filed Complete Specification on 12.05.2012`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: `The applicant filed a petition under 138 of the prevailing Rules and submitted the Complete Specification on
        12.06.2012`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: `None of the above`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q13]",
    question: `  As per The Patent Act, the qualification required for a Registered Patent Agent to work as the Technical
    Member of the Appellate Board is:`,
    correctAnswer: "b",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: `Master degree in Science with at least 8 years functioned as a Registered Patent Agent`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `Degree in Engineering or technology or Master degree in Science with at least 10 years functioned as a Regis-
        tered Patent Agent`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: `Degree in Engineering or technology or Master degree in Science with at least 10 years functioned as a Regis-
        tered Patent Agent`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: `All of the above`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q14]",
    question: ` As per the Patent Act, Register of Patents shall contain:`,
    correctAnswer: "d",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: `Names and addresses of grantees of Patents`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `Revocations of Patents`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: `Notification of Assignments and of transmissions of Patents`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: `All of the above`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q15]",
    question: ` Any person interested may make an application to the Controller for granting compulsory licence on Patent
    as per The Patent Act, in the following grounds:`,
    correctAnswer: "a",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: ` That the Patented invention is not available to the public at reasonably affordable price`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `That the Patented invention is reserved for noncommercial purpose`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: ` That the Patented invention is imported with immediate effect`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: ` None of the above`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q16]",
    question: `A researcher finds an idea on recycling of biodegradable plastic. How does he proceed for patenting his
    idea?`,
    correctAnswer: "b",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: ` He needs to publish in the Scientific Journal and has to wait for invitation from Patent Office`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `He needs to submit Provisional Specification and subsequently to file Complete Specification before Patent
        Office`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: ` Both A and B`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: ` None of the above`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q17]",
    question: `The “invention” as per Patent Act, 1970 incorporates:`,
    correctAnswer: "d",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: `Capable of Industrial application`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `An inventive step`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: `A new product or process`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: ` All of the above`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q18]",
    question: ` Identify from the following patented products, for which compulsory licence are available for export which
    is entitled for manufacture and export to any country having insufficient / no manufacturing capacity to address
    public health problems as per The Patent Act:`,
    correctAnswer: "b",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: ` Disaster management related device`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `Pharmaceutical products`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: ` Food products`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: ` All of the above`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q19]",
    question: ` When a Patent completes its full term of 20 years within the provision of The Patent Act, it:`,
    correctAnswer: "d",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: ` May be renewed for a further period of 10 years`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `May be renewed only under special circumstances`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: ` May be renewed for a period of 5 years`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: ` Shall not be renewed`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q20]",
    question: ` A ceased Patent due to non-payment of renewal fees, may be restored by filing an application for resto-
    ration with prescribed fee as per The Patent Act:`,
    correctAnswer: "b",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: `Within 12 months from the date on which Patent ceased to have effect`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `Within 18 months from the date on which Patent ceased to have effect`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: ` Within 48 months from the date on which Patent ceased to have effect`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: ` None of the above`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 21,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q21]",
    question: ` The submission of proof of right to make an application for a Patent made by virtue of an assignment as
    per the Act shall be within a prescribed period of:`,
    correctAnswer: "c",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: `With the application or within 3 months from date of application`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `With the application or 9 months from date of application`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: ` With the application or 6 months from date of application`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: ` With the application or 12 months from date of application`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 22,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q22]",
    question: ` Find out from the following which is not the ground for opposition under Section 25(1) of Patent Act, 1970:`,
    correctAnswer: "a",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: `That the request for examination pursuant to the filing of Complete Specification has not been filed by the
        applicant himself`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `That the Complete Specification does not sufficiently and clearly describe the invention or the method by
        which it is to be performed`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: ` That the applicant has failed to disclose to the Controller the information required by section 8 or has fur-
        nished the information which in any material particular was false to his knowledge`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: ` That the Patentee or the person under or through whom he claims, wrongfully obtained the invention or any
        part thereof from him or from a person under or through whom he claims`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 23,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q23]",
    question: ` International application as per the Patent Act, 1970 means:`,
    correctAnswer: "c",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: `An application filed in WTO`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `An application filed under Hague agreement`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: ` An application for Patent made in accordance with the Patent Cooperation Treaty`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: ` An application for Patent made in accordance with the Budapest Treaty`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 24,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q24]",
    question: ` Discovery of a new galaxy is not Patentable:`,
    correctAnswer: "a",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: `As per section 3(c) of The Patent Act, 1970`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `As per section 3(k) of The Patent Act, 1970`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: `As per section 3(d) of The Patent Act, 1970`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: ` As per section 3(b) of The Patent Act, 1970`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    id: 25,
    paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C, Q25]",
    question: ` Definition of “Capable of industrial application”, in relation to an invention as per The Patent Act means:`,
    correctAnswer: "a",
    options: [
      {
        id: "a",
        text: ` That the invention is capable of being made or used in an industry`,
      },
      {
        id: "b",
        text: `That the invention is capable of being manufactured in an industry`,
      },
      {
        id: "c",
        text: `That the invention is capable of being sold by an industry`,
      },
      {
        id: "d",
        text: `None of the above`,
      },
    ],
  },
];
// {
//   id: 7,
//   paperDetails: "[2018, Paper 1, Set C]",
//   question: `As per The Patent Act, 1970 the first compulsory licence granted in India to:`,
//   correctAnswer: "a",
//   options: [
//     {
//       id: "a",
//       text: `Natco Pharma on 9th March, 2012`,
//     },
//     {
//       id: "b",
//       text: `Cipla on 9th March, 2009`,
//     },
//     {
//       id: "c",
//       text: `Glenmark on 27th January, 2009`,
//     },
//     {
//       id: "d",
//       text: `None of the above`,
//     },
//   ],
// },
